Avengers: Secret Wars is a science fiction, action,
adventure film directed by Anthony Russo.
An upcoming film in Phase Six of the Marvel Cinematic Universe
(MCU) and the finale of The Multiverse Saga.
Victor von Doom  / Doctor Doom, played by Robert Downey Jr..
Reed Richards / Mr. Fantastic, played by Pedro Pascal.
Sue Storm / The Invisible Woman, played by Vanessa Kirby.
Ben Grimm / Thing, played by Ebon Moss-Bachrach.
Johnny Storm / The Human Torch, played by Joseph Quinn.
Bucky Barnes / Winter Soldier, played by Sebastian Stan.
Avengers: Doomsday and Avengers: Secret Wars are American superhero films based on the Marvel Comics superhero team the
Avengers, produced by Marvel Studios and AGBO, and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
They are respectively the fifth and sixth installments in the Avengers film series following Avengers:
Endgame (2019), and the 39th and 40th films of the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
Both films are directed by Anthony and Joe Russo from
screenplays by Michael Waldron and Stephen McFeely.
They feature an ensemble cast composed of many previous MCU actors, headlined by Vanessa Kirby, Anthony Mackie,
Letitia Wright, Ebon Moss-Bachrach, Simu Liu, Joseph Quinn, Pedro Pascal, and Robert Downey Jr.
In Doomsday, the Avengers, Wakandans, Fantastic Four, New Avengers,
and the X-Men team up to face Doctor Doom (Downey).
Two new Avengers films, The Kang Dynasty and Secret Wars, were announced in July 2022
as the conclusion of the MCU's Phase Six and "The Multiverse Saga".
Destin Daniel Cretton was hired to direct The Kang Dynasty and Jonathan Majors
was set to reprise his MCU role as the villain Kang the Conqueror.
Jeff Loveness was hired to write The Kang Dynasty that September and
Waldron was hired to write Secret Wars a month later.
In November 2023, Cretton departed, Waldron replaced Loveness as writer of The Kang Dynasty as well, and Marvel was considering
moving away from the Kang storyline in part due to Majors's legal issues; Majors was fired the following month.
The return of the Russo brothers as directors and McFeely as co-writer, the casting of Downey as new villain
Doctor Doom, and the new subtitle Doomsday for the first film were all announced in July 2024.
Both films are being produced at Pinewood Studios in England.
Filming for Doomsday took place from April to September 2025, and
filming for Secret Wars is scheduled to begin in mid-2026.
Jeffrey Ford is editing the films and Alan Silvestri is composing the
musical score for them, both returning from previous MCU films.
Avengers: Doomsday is scheduled for release on December 18, 2026, and Avengers: Secret Wars is
scheduled for release on December 17, 2027, both part of Phase Six of the MCU.
The film explores themes of superhero, based on comic, sequel,
superhero team, marvel cinematic universe (mcu).
The tone is thought_provoking.